<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travisj.nyc</title>
    <description>husband. father. engineer. jogger.
</description>
    <link>http://travisj.nyc/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://travisj.nyc/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 17:37:41 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 17:37:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kenneth at 16 Months</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_DSC_7831.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kenneth in the park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenneth is a bit over 16 months old right now and he is so much fun to be with. He is learning new things everyday and is currently focused on jumping. He’s been able to get off the ground with both feet a few times and can usually land without falling over. He also tries to repeat many different words that we say, not quite getting them right just yet, but he’s working on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_DSC_7836.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kenneth jumping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He and I are starting to settle into a routine. When he wakes up, I make him scrambled eggs and toast for breakfast. I always ask him if he wants eggs and he always responds with a quick “yeah!”. I think go to work and get home about 90 minutes before bedtime. Rachel makes us dinner and then Ken and I get some time to play and watch a few minutes of cartoons before he heads off to bed. He’s a happy guy, always up for anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the weekends, Ken and I get to spend a lot more time together. We usually go to a few different playgrounds and lately have been meeting up with Rachel for breakfast after she coaches for Moms in Training up at Brooklyn Bridge Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_DSC_6946.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swinging&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_IMG_9317.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the playground&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_DSC_7064.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hamming it up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_DSC_7368.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Watching TV&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_IMG_9632.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In the tubes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160529_IMG_9575.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sliding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 16:47:31 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/2016/05/29/kenneth-at-16-months.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/2016/05/29/kenneth-at-16-months.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>And We&#39;re Off!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rachel, Kenneth and I leave for Paris in a couple hours. We’re packed and all our plans are in order. Nothing left to do except get excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are taking the overnight flight to Paris and spending the rest of the day wandering around. We plan on visting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.centrepompidou.fr/en&quot;&gt;Centre Pompidou&lt;/a&gt; and a playground or two for Kenneth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to Paris, we are going to spend some time in Western France, Vienna, Prague and Amesterdam. Be on the lookup for more updates here and lots of pictures from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/rljart/&quot;&gt;Rachel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/travisj&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 14:23:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/euro2016/2016/03/26/and-were-off.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/euro2016/2016/03/26/and-were-off.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>euro2016</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Darkroom Filter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was editing a photo in &lt;a href=&quot;http://usedarkroom.com/&quot;&gt;Darkroom&lt;/a&gt; last night and came across the filter sharing feature. Darkroom allows you to create and save your own photo filter. After you’ve created the filter, you have the option to share it on Facebook, Instagram or Twitter. That’s neat, but the thing that is the coolest is the way you share the filter. Darkroom adds a QR code to your photo and you then share the photo. A user that wants to install your filter then takes a screenshot of the QR code and opens Darkroom. That’s it, the filter is magically installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160319_IMG_8952.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;my filter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of interest, I used a QR code reader to see what content was being encoded and it is a simple URL to open the Darkroom app and install the filter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;darkroom:///install_filter?id=441&quot;&gt;darkroom:///install_filter?id=441&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 13:09:34 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/2016/03/19/darkroom-filter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/2016/03/19/darkroom-filter.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Birthday Crusher!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160313_DSC_2009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crusher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is Crusher’s eighth birthday. He’s been a loyal family member since the day we picked him up all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 13:54:38 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/crusher/2016/03/13/happy-birthday-crusher.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/crusher/2016/03/13/happy-birthday-crusher.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>crusher</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bread Success</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t plan to post everytime I bake bread, but Rachel and I have further refined our recipe and had a near-perfect raisin walnut sourdough bread this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160312_DSC_1869.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;raisin walnut sourdough&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added an extra 75 grams of flour, 575g total, and cooked the bread for an hour at 450 degrees. The key we found with our oven is to put a baking sheet under the dutch oven to prevent the bottom of the bread from burning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bread fresh out of the oven makes for a pretty awesome breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:07:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/2016/03/12/bread-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/2016/03/12/bread-success.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Morning Run</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fairly dissapointing run. I’ve been having knee pain, which is why I have been resting it and not running, and I could tell pretty early on that it was not gone. I had hopes of running 12 miles tomorrow, but I think it is best for me to rest it for another week. I have the Paris Marathon coming up in three weeks and given my complete lack of training, a couple more runs here or there is not going to make a difference. The only thing I can hope for now is that I show up to the start line as healthy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 01:54:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/training/2016/03/12/MorningRun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/training/2016/03/12/MorningRun.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>training</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sourdough Bread Notes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/02/28/weekend-update&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt; that I started baking my own sourdough bread from my own starter. I’ve now been at it for two weeks and think the bread is really starting to come along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I prepared the dough for a basic sourdough bread, based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theclevercarrot.com/2014/01/sourdough-bread-a-beginners-guide/&quot;&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt;. I put in a bit more flour than the recipe called for because of a previous trial with the recipe and think it was about right, but will maybe do a bit less next time. Given that it’s winter and a bit colder, I let bulk fermentation go for about 14 hours. I then split the dough in half and baked the first loaf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160307_DSC_1824.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;first loaf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160307_DSC_1828.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;first loaf cut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first loaf baked in the dutch oven with the lid on for 60 minutes. Since our oven has been burning the bread, I set the oven to about 410°F and the temperature seemed about right this time. It still came out a bit overdone on the outside and maybe a touch underdone inside. The sourdough flavor is starting to show in these latest loaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160307_DSC_1825.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;second loaf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second loaf got an extra hour for the second rise and I baked it for only 50 minutes and came out looking perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 16:24:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/2016/03/06/sourdough-bread-notes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/2016/03/06/sourdough-bread-notes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Morning Run</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First run after my right knee injury so I took it easy for the first two miles. At that point, I changed the pace up to a tempo run to see how things felt. I actually felt better at the faster speed. Overall, my knee does not feel as healed as I would like. I am not experiencing any pain, but it feels a bit more sore than ideal. I plan to rest tomorrow and see how things feel this weekend for a five to eight mile run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 01:44:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/training/2016/03/03/MorningRun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/training/2016/03/03/MorningRun.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>training</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekend Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth and I got to spend more quality time together this weekend. We took Crusher for a couple walks and inspected the bark of nearly every tree along the way. Crusher does not mind the slowness involved with bark inspection since he’s usually on the hunt for the next smell to track down. The weather was really nice this weekend, so I didn’t mind the slow stroll with the boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When inside, we played a lot of music!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160228_IMG_8764.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;ken with his microphone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel and I recently watched Cooked, the documentary based on the book by Michael Pollan. It was a great series and I was especially drawn to the part where he makes his own bread. We looked up a few recipes and started making our own sourdough starter last weekend and this weekend got to start making the bread. The loaves turned out well enough that they could pass for bread, but not quite sourdough. I think the starter has to grow a bit more. It was fun making the bread and trying to improve on each loaf as I created it. More to come here, I’m sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started watching the talks from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MGuKhcnrqGA&amp;amp;list=PLb0IAmt7-GS0M8Q95RIc2lOM6nc77q1IY&quot;&gt;React.js Conf 2016&lt;/a&gt; this weekend and am pretty excited about the upcoming possibilities with React. I am especially excited about the “learn once, write anywhere” ideas behind the framework as it grows beyond just the web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we trekked into the city today to visit friends in the hospital that just had a baby. It was fun to be back at the same hospital where Ken was born and think back to when we started our life with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20160228_IMG_8777.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;ken at langone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 22:17:03 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/2016/02/28/weekend-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/2016/02/28/weekend-update.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kenneth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth is growing up! He’s about 14 months old and walking all over the apartment. He loves playing with magnets, balls and all my electronics. He is so much fun to be with, but it’s also nice that he still naps twice a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few pictures I’ve taken of him over the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_8630.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cool glasses&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSC_1347.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bath time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSC_1397.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;toys&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSC_1522.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;new shoes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSC_1612.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;big smile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSC_1623.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;choco mouth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSC_1703.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;playground with mom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 19:22:48 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://travisj.nyc/2016/02/27/kenneth.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://travisj.nyc/2016/02/27/kenneth.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
